tealium.com 2017-11-07

# Privacy Policy | Tealium

### **Tealium Inc. Website Privacy Statement**

Privacy Statement Effective as of  September 29, 2016

Tealium Inc. (“ **Tealium** ”) is committed to protecting the privacy of individuals who visit Tealium’s website ([http://tealium.com](http://www.tealium.com/)) (“ **Tealium Website** ”) and individuals who use the Services as defined below. This Tealium Website Privacy Statement describes Tealium’s privacy practices in relation to the use of the Tealium Website and the related services offered by Tealium, which services are accessible via the Tealium Website (the “ **Services** ”). The Tealium Website may contain links to other websites. The privacy statements of such other websites govern the content and use of information of those websites. Tealium encourages you to review the privacy statements of such other websites to understand their information practices. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. Tealium will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Tealium Website Privacy Statement.

**1\. Information We May Collect From You**

Tealium collects individually identifiable information (“Personal Information”) from: (i) individuals who visit the Tealium Website (“ **Site Visitors** ”) and (ii) individuals who use the Services (“ **Customers** ”).

**SITE VISITORS**  
Tealium may collect information from your computer or mobile device as you navigate the Tealium Website through the use of commonly used website information-gathering tools, such as cookies and web beacons (“ **Web Collection Information** ”). The Web Collection Information includes information from your web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on the Tealium Website (such as the web pages viewed and the links clicked). You can read more detailed information about how we use web beacons and cookies and the purpose for which we use them here.

**CUSTOMERS**  
Tealium may ask you to provide Tealium with personal contact information, such as name, company name, address, phone number, and email address (“ **Contact Information** ”) if you request additional information about the Services or register to use the Services. If you purchase the Services, Tealium may require you to provide financial and billing information, such as billing name and address, company bank account number, credit card number, and the number of employees within the organization that will be using the Services (“ **Financial Information** ”). Tealium may also ask you to provide additional information, such as number of website visitors or number of employees (“ **Other Customer Information** ”). Contact Information, Financial Information, and Other Customer Information are referred to collectively as “ **Customer Information** ”.

**USER GENERATED CONTENT**  
Some areas of our website allow you to provide content to us directly, for example, where comments are left on a bulletin board, blog or chat room on our website (a “ **Public Forum** ”). In using any Public Forum on the Tealium Website you give your consent that any Personal Information you submit about yourself or any third party may be read, collected, or otherwise used by anyone who reads that Public Forum. We will not be responsible for any Personal Information that is posted on a publicly viewable Public Forum. To request removal of any Personal Information from any Public Forum, contact us at [privacy@tealium.com](mailto:privacy@tealium.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**2\. How We Use Collected Information**

Tealium uses Customer Information to perform the Services requested. For example, if you fill out the web form on our Contact Me page, Tealium will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the Services. Tealium may also use Customer Information for marketing purposes. For example, Tealium may use information you provide to contact you to discuss your interest in the Services and to send you information about Tealium, its partners and other information such as current promotions or events. You can read more detailed information about how to manage how we use Customer Information for marketing purposes here.

Tealium uses Financial Information solely to check your financial qualifications and collect payment for the Services.

Tealium uses Web Collection Information to operate and improve the Tealium Websites. Tealium may also use Web Collection Information alone or in combination with Customer Information to provide personalized information about Tealium and the Services. To read more about Tealium’s use of Web Collection Information, please click here.

Tealium may use Customer Information and Web Collection Information to enforce Tealium Website policies, or to protect Tealium’s intellectual property and other rights or the rights of others using the Tealium Websites or the Services.  

**3\. Web Collection Information**

This section describes the types of Web Collection Information used on the Tealium Web Site and in connection with the Services, and how this information may be used.

This section describes the types of Web Collection Information used on the Tealium Website and in connection with the Services, and how this information may be use

**Cookies**  
Tealium uses cookies to make your interactions with the Tealium Website easy and helpful. When you visit the Tealium Website, Tealium’s servers send a cookie to your device. Client-side tracking objects (commonly called cookies or JavaScript files) are small text files located in your browser directory that may be placed on your device. Each cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a value (usually a unique number). For a more thorough explanation of what cookies are and how they operate, please visit aboutcookies.org or [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). On their own, cookies do not personally identify you; they recognize your browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to Tealium, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or filling out a web form (such as “Contact Me”), you remain anonymous to Tealium. You have the ability to manage the use of cookies on your computer using controls in your browser. To learn more about how to manage cookies, visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Tealium uses cookies that are session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session, i.e., only while you are reading or navigating the Tealium Website. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you close your browser or turn off your computer. Using your browser, you may disable the use of cookies, delete cookies, or individually reject cookies at any time. You may also disable JavaScript at any time. However some features of our website may not function properly unless cookies and JavaScript are enabled and some areas of our website may not function at all. In addition, you may not be able to successfully use the Services.

The following describes how Tealium may use different categories of cookies and your options for managing cookies’ settings:

Cookies that are used as part of the Services (in the proxy) may include cookies of a third party website that is being co-browsed, for example, in order to deliver the website as intended by the third party website operator. The cookie practices of such websites are governed by their own respective privacy statements. Tealium encourages you to review the privacy statements of other websites to understand their information practices.

The following describes how Tealium may use different categories of cookies and your options for managing cookies’ settings:

**Type of Cookies** | **Description** | **Managing Settings**  
---|---|---  
Required Cookies | Required cookies enable you to navigate the Tealium Website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Tealium Website and using the Services. 

If you have agreed to identify yourself to Tealium, Tealium uses cookies containing encrypted information to allow Tealium to uniquely identify you. Each time you log into the Services, a cookie containing an encrypted, unique identifier that is tied to your account is placed on your browser. These cookies allow Tealium to uniquely identify you when you are logged into the Services and to process your online transactions and requests.

| Required cookies are essential to operate the Tealium Website and the Services, there is no option to opt out of these cookies.  
Performance cookies | Performance cookies collect information about how Site Visitors use the Tealium Website, including which pages Site Visitors go to most often and if they receive error messages from certain pages. These cookies do not collect information that individually identifies a Site Visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and anonymous. It is only used to improve how the Tealium Website functions and performs. 

Tealium may engage third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from Site Visitors. Tealium may also utilize Flash cookies for these purposes. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.

| To learn how to opt out of functionality cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Note that opting out may impact the functionality you receive when visiting the Tealium Website.  
Functionality cookies | Functionality cookies allow the Tealium Website to remember information you have entered or choices you make (such as your username, language, or your region) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies also enable you to optimize your use of the Services after logging in. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize. 

Tealium’s Privacy Widget provides control and flexibility for opt-in or opt-out choices to Site Visitors. Site Visitors can choose which tags or categories of tags they want to enable while you browse the Tealium Website.

Tealium may use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on the Tealium Website to personalize your visit. If you disable Flash cookies, you may not have access to some features that make your visit to the Tealium Website efficient.

| To learn how to opt out of functionality cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Note that opting out may impact the functionality you receive when visiting the Tealium Website. 

To learn more about Tealium’s Privacy Widget, click here.

Cookie management tools provided by your browser may not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).

Privacy Widget Not Loaded  
  
Targeting or Advertising cookies | Tealium may engage third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from Site Visitors. 

Analytics: Tealium may use cookies delivered by third parties to track the performance of Tealium’s advertisements. For example, these cookies remember which browsers have visited the Tealium Website. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after Tealium receives it.

Marketing solutions: Tealium may also contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from the Tealium Website, from emails, and on third-party websites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time by collecting Web Collection Information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other websites. This process also helps Tealium manage and track the effectiveness of its marketing efforts.

Tealium may also partner with third parties to provide certain features on the Tealium Websites or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity. Such third parties may use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Retargeting cookies: Retargeting is a cookie-based technology that uses JavaScript code to follow Site Visitors as they use the internet.

| To learn more about advertising networks and their opt out instructions, click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). 

To learn how to opt out of these cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).  
  
Tracking and other cookies | The Services use hashed tags or an anonymized tracking identifier that ties to cookies that are used on Customers’ website that allow Customers to manage the data gathered about their website visitors and take action to improve their experiences. Customers are responsible for complying with any legal requirements in using hashed tags and cookies. 

The Services may also use tracking pixels embedded by our Customers in their on-line advertising, often distributed to third party web sites using ad exchanges, that allow our Customers to gather data about viewers of their on-line advertisements.

| To learn how to opt out of these cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).  
  
Cookies that are used as part of the Services (in the proxy) may include cookies of a third party website that is being co-browsed, for example, in order to deliver the website as intended by the third party website operator. The cookie practices of such websites are governed by their own respective privacy statements. Tealium encourages you to review the privacy statements of other websites to understand their information practices.

**Web Beacons**  
Tealium, or third parties with whom we contract, may use web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about Customers and Site Visitors’ use of the Tealium Website and interaction with emails from Tealium. Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collecting information about website usage, e-mail response and tracking. For example, Tealium may place web beacons in marketing emails that notify Tealium when you click on a link in the email that directs you to the Tealium Website. Tealium uses web beacons to operate and improve the Tealium Website and email communications.

**IP Addresses and URLs  
**Like many other websites, we collect information about our Site Visitors’ utilization and navigation of the Tealium Website. This information helps us to design the Tealium Website to better suit our Site Visitors’ needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer the Tealium Website, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences. For example, Tealium uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Customers and Site Visitors navigate the Tealium Website.

Tealium may collect aggregated data regarding use of the Services and the Tealium Website, including, without limitation, number of Site Visitors, frequency and patterns of use, tag usage, feedback request trends, etc. (“ **Aggregated Data** ”). Tealium uses Aggregated Data as a statistical measure and not in a manner that would identify you personally. Aggregated Data enables us to determine how often certain parts of the Tealium Website or the Services are used so that we can improve them. Tealium may make use of, or make such Aggregated Data available to, third parties, in any manner in our sole discretion.

**Social Media Features  
**The Tealium Website may use social media features, such as the Facebook ‘like’ button (facebook.com), Linkedin (linkedin.com), and Twitter (twitter.com) (“ **Social Media Features** ”). These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on the Tealium Website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. You may be given the option by such Social Media Features to post information about your activities on the Tealium Website to your profile page that is provided by a third party Social Media network in order to share with others within your network. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Tealium Website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant Social Media Features.

**4\. Public Forums and Customer Testimonials**

Tealium may provide Public Forums on the Tealium Website. Any Personal Information you choose to submit in a Public Forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these Public Forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. Tealium is not responsible for the Personal Information you choose to submit in these Public Forums. Customers and Site Visitors may elect to use Tealium’s referral program to inform friends about the Tealium Website and the Services. When using the referral program, Tealium may request the friend’s name and email address. Tealium will automatically send the friend an email inviting him or her to visit the Tealium Website, or will share with them via email the information you have requested to be shared. Tealium does not share this information with other parties.

Tealium posts a list of Customers and testimonials on the Tealium Websites that contain information such as Customer names, photos and testimonials. Tealium obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

**5\. How We Share Information Collected**

**Service Providers**  
Tealium may share Customer Information with Tealium’s contracted service providers, such as payment processors, so that these service providers can provide services on our behalf. Tealium may also share Customer Information with Tealium’s service providers to ensure the quality of information provided. Unless described in this Privacy Statement, Tealium does not share, sell, rent, or trade any information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

**Tealium Affiliates**  
Tealium may share Customer Information with other members and affiliates of the Tealium corporate group in order to work with them, including affiliates of the Tealium corporate group. For example, Tealium may need to share Customer Information for customer relationship management purposes.

**Partners and Affiliated Businesses Not Controlled by Tealium**  
Tealium may partner with other companies to jointly offer products or services. If you purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly offered product or service from Tealium, Tealium may share Customer Information collected in connection with your purchase or expression of interest with our partners. Tealium does not control our partners’ use of the Customer Information, and their use of the information will be in accordance with their own privacy policies. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner, you may choose not to purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly offered product or service.

**Billing**  
Tealium may use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use Financial Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on Tealium’s behalf.

**Compelled Disclosure**  
It may be necessary for Tealium to disclose your Personal Information, either by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence. Tealium may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate. Tealium may also disclose Personal Information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users.

**6\. Global Data Transfers, Storage and Processing – Privacy Shield**

To facilitate Tealium’s global operations, Tealium may transfer and access Customer Information from around the world, including the United States. This Privacy Statement shall apply even if Tealium transfers Customer Information to other countries.

Wherever we transfer, store or process your Personal Information, we will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your Personal Information. When using or disclosing Personal Information transferred from the European Union, we adopt appropriate measures under European Union law for ensuring adequate safeguards, or obtain your consent. For European Site Visitors and Customers, your Personal Information may be transferred outside of the European Union in order to provide the information or Services you request from us. By visiting the Tealium Website or using the Services, you agree to Tealium transferring your Personal Information outside of the European Union.

**Privacy Shield Adherence and Certification**

Tealium participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (Privacy Shield) and Swiss Safe Harbor. Tealium is committed to subjecting all personal information received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield and the Swiss Safe Harbor, to the applicable Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, recourse, enforcement and liability.   To learn more about the Privacy Shield and view Tealium’s  certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield at [https://www.privacyshield.gov/Program-Overview](https://www.privacyshield.gov/Program-Overview). To learn more about the Swiss Safe Harbor and view Tealium’ s certification the Swiss Safe Harbor, visit [https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx](https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx).

Tealium is responsible for the processing of Personal Information it receives, under the Privacy Shield, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Tealium complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of Personal Information from the European Union, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to Personal Information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield, Tealium is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Tealium may be required to disclose Personal Information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Tealium has designated the Chief Legal Officer to oversee its information security program including its compliance with the Privacy Shield program and Swiss Safe Harbor.  The Chief Legal Officer, shall review and approve any material changes to compliance with the Shield or to this Privacy Policy.  Any questions, concerns, or comments regarding this Privacy Policy may be submitted to privacy@tealium.com.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not satisfactorily addressed, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint%22%20%5Ct%20%22_blank)), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

In accordance with its internal company policies, Tealium commits to cooperate with the European Union data protection authorities (DPA’s) with regard to human resources data transferred from the European Union in the context of the employment relationship and including Tealium employees located in the United Kingdom effective at date of data collected.

**7\. Use of the Tealium Web Site by Children**

Tealium does not sell products for purchase by children. If we learn that we have collected the Personal Information of a child under 13 without first receiving verifiable parental consent we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

**8\. Your Control and Choices – Do Not Track (DNT)**

You may correct, update and delete your Customer Information, change your choices for alerts and other messages, choose whether to receive offers and promotions from us or you may request access to the Personal Information we hold about you and ask us to amend or delete such Personal Information. You can send your request to [support@tealium.com](mailto:support@tealium.com). Tealium offers Site Visitors and Customers who provide contact information a means to choose how Tealium uses the information provided. You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking [here](https://tealium.com/unsubscribe) or by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of Tealium’s marketing emails. Additionally, you may send a request specifying your communications preferences to [support@tealium.com](mailto:support@tealium.com). Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with Tealium or the Services.

To update Financial Information or have your registration information deleted, please email [support@tealium.com](mailto:support@tealium.com). To discontinue your account, please email [support@tealium.com](mailto:support@tealium.com). Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be handled within 30 days.

Tealium honors Do Not Track (DNT) headers and allows its users to opt‐out of having their personal information collected by Tealium. Tealium also provides its customers guidelines and instructions on how to honor DNT headers. The behavior of utag.js can be altered to track only analytic data and not track individual visitors. Tealium’s website honors DNT and is compliant with [California Assembly Bill](http://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=201320140AB370) [370](http://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=201320140AB370).

More information about DNT: <http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_not_track_header>

<http://donottrack.us/>

Note: It is not necessary to provide notice or choice when disclosure is made to a third party that is acting as an agent to perform task(s) on behalf of and under the instructions of Tealium. The Onward Transfer Principle, on the other hand, does apply to such disclosures.

**9\. Data Retention**

Tealium retains the information we receive as described in this Privacy Statement for as long as needed to provide our Services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, and enforce our agreements.

**10\. Customer Data**

As part of using our Services, Customers may submit electronic data or information to the Services (“ **Customer Data** ”) that constitutes Personal Information of other individuals to us. Such data may include an individual’s name, email address, or phone number. Tealium has no direct relationship with the individuals to whom Customer Data may pertain, which we process on the behalf of our Customers. Any uses of Customer Data by Tealium are done so pursuant to Tealium’s subscription agreement in place between Tealium and the relevant Customer, which agreement exclusively governs Tealium’s treatment of Customer Data and supersedes this Privacy Statement in case of conflict, or as required by law. If Personal Information pertaining to you as an individual has been submitted to us by a Customer as Customer Data and you wish to exercise any rights you may have to access, correct, amend, or delete such data, please inquire with the Customer directly.

**11\. Security**

Tealium takes precautions, including administrative, technical, and physical measures – to help safeguard Customer Information against loss, theft, and misuse as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. While we follow generally accepted standards to protect information submitted to us, no method of storage or transmission is 100% secure. Users are solely responsible for protecting their passwords, limiting access to their computers, and signing out of the Services after their sessions.

**12\. Changes to this Privacy Statement**

From time to time, we may change this Privacy Statement to accommodate new technologies, industry practices, regulatory requirements or for other purposes. When we change the privacy statement in a material way, a notice will be posted on the Tealium Website along with the updated privacy statement.

**13\. Privacy Questions**

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of the Tealium Website please contact Tealium’s privacy team at [privacy@tealium.com](mailto:privacy@tealium.com) or by mailing Tealium’s Privacy Office, 11095 Torreyana Road, San Diego, CA 92121.
